Finding Aid for Ernest James McCall papers, 1897-1900 and 1918-1950
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Ernest James McCall papers 1897-1900 and 1918-1950
McCall, Ernest James, 1873-1950
.3 linear feet
851736 Aa 2
Correspondence and miscellanea relating to Michigan Republican politics and to his journalistic career.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Donor: 5427
No further additions to the records are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Newspaperman from Mount Pleasant, Isabella County, and Grand Haven, Ottawa County.
Correspondence, and miscellanea relating to Michigan Republican politics, particularly to the election of 1918, and to his journalistic career; also student papers.
Subjects:
Elections--Michigan--1918.; Grand Haven (Mich.); Isabella County (Mich.); Journalists--Michigan--Grand Haven.; Journalists--Michigan--Mount Pleasant.; Michigan--Politics and government--1917-1921.; Michigan--Politics and government--1922-1928.; Michigan--Politics and government--1929-1938.; Mount Pleasant (Mich.); American newspapers--Michigan--Grand Haven.; Ottawa County (Mich.); American newspapers--Michigan--Mount Pleasant.; Republican Party (Mich.); Michigan--Politics and government--1837-1950.
Contributors:
Currie, Gilbert, 1882-1960.; DeFoe, Murl Holcomb, 1879-; Hoffman, Clare Eugene, 1875-1967.; Knox, Frank, 1874-1944.; McCall, Jonathan Nicholson, b. 1857.; Mapes, Carl Edgar, 1874-1939.; Miller, Floyd Josiah, 1886-1954.; Newberry, Truman Handy, 1864-1945.; Townsend, Charles Elroy, 1856-1924.; Tufty, Esther Van Wagoner, d. 1986.; Vandenberg, Arthur H. (Arthur Hendrick), 1884-1951.; Woodruff, Roy Orchard, 1876-1953.
- Correspondence
  - 1918 (Box 1)
  - 1919 (Box 1)
  - 1920 (Box 1)
  - 1921 (Box 1)
  - 1922-1923 (Box 1)
  - 1924-1926 (Box 1)
  - 1927 (Box 1)
  - 1928-1929 (Box 1)
  - 1930-1931 (Box 1)
  - 1932-1939 (Box 1)
  - 1940-1945 (Box 1)
  - 1946-1950 (Box 1)
- Student papers
  - 1897-1900, 14 folders (Box 1)
- Miscellanea
  - Miscellaneous writings (Box 1)
  - Obituary notices, 1950 (Box 1)
  - Miscellanea, 2 folders (Box 1)
Selective Index to Correspondences
Currie, Gilbert Archibald, 1882-1960.
1918, 1919, 1920
DeFoe, Murl Holcomb, 1879-
March 24, 1922; December 26, 1925
Hoffman, Clare Eugene, 1875-1967-
April 27, 1937
Knox, Frank, 1874-1944.
September 19, 1935.
McCall, Jonathan Nicholson, 1857-
1918-1927.
Mapes, Carl-,Edgar, 1874-1939.
March 17, November 21, November 26, 1927; April 16, 1931; December 9,1932
Miller, Floyd Josiah, 1886-1954.
October 6, 1929
Newberry, Truman Handy, 1864-1945.
June 6, 1921; April 24, 1922
Townsend, Charles Elroy, 1856-1924.
December 24, 1919
Tufty, Esther (Van Wagoner)
May 10, 1937
Vandenberg, Arthur Hendrick, 1884-1951.
October 23, 1923; April 6, April 19, 1928; April 19, July 29,1947
Woodruff, Roy Orchard, 1876-1953.
November 23, 1921